A Guide to the Great Falls Historical Society, Virginia Collection, c.1960s-2022
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
- Series 8: Photographic Materials, c.1960s -2001
  - Sub-series 8-5: Oversize Photographs, 1977-1980
    - GFPARK-023 - Postcard copy "Great Falls Inn & Iron Foundry Ruins, Great Falls of the Potomac, Va. 15 miles from Washington, D.C. on the Washington & Old Dominion Railway.", Undated
    - GFPARK-027 - Overlook Tower at Great Falls, Flood of 1936., Undated
    - GFPARK-028 - A sign in Great Falls Park., Undated
    - GFPARK-029 - Great Falls Park, Virginia Shore, showing the pavilion, Great Falls Inn, tower, and carousel, July 21, 1931., Undated
    - GFPARK-030 - Camp meeting at Great Falls Park circa 1906. Back row: Earl Sanders, Billy Reid (Earl's grandfather), William Lanham, Phoebe Wynkoop, Ben Lanham, Rose Reid (Earl's mother), and possibly Rose Lanham. Front row: Laura Jenkins, Marvin Sanders (Earl's brother), and Effie Lanham. Laura and Marvin were later married., Undated
    - GP-019 - Omnibus at Great Falls Park., Undated
    - GRANG-001 - Great Falls Grange Members, L.B. Morris, Mark Turner, Joseph Shroy, O.K. Miller, O.V. Carper, Mr. Preston, D.D. Cornwell, Michael Shirkey, G.E. Gardner, W.C. Walker, S.M. Follin Sr., A.C. Speight, J. Marvin Sanders in 1929., Undated
    - GRANG-002 - Great Falls Grange Members, L.B. Morris, Mark Turner, Joseph Shroy, O.K. Miller, O.V. Carper, Mr. Preston, D.D. Cornwell, Michael Shirkey, G.E. Gardner, W.C. Walker, S.M. Follin Sr., A.C. Speight, J. Marvin Sanders in 1929., Undated
    - GRANG-010 - Great Falls Grange., 1977 October
    - HOME-003 - Corder House on Colvin Run Road in 1980., 1980
    - JENK-001 - 1923 Family reunion at Dranesville Tavern, Samuel and Catherine Jenkins with their children., Undated
    - LEIGH-004 - Dr. Alfred Leigh's House at Walker Road and Colvin Run Road in 1979., 1979 April
    - MILLER-002 - Mr. and Mrs. O.K. Miller on their 60th or 62nd wedding anniversary., Undated
    - NIKE-001 - Nike missile control site on Springvale Road., c. 1979-1980
    - POST-002 - Log house at the corner of Beach Mill Road and Springvale Road once the Deanwood Post Office., 1979 April
    - RECACT-002 - Great Falls Majorettes and Drum Corps. posing in front of Washington Plaza Baptist Church in Reston, Va., Undated
    - REID-003 - Baseball team. Standing far right is Mitchell Reid., Undated
    - STORE-009 - Harrison's Store at Dranesville on Route 7 where Harrison's gas station is today. L to R: W.O. Harrison Jr., W.O. Harrison Sr., Iva Jenkins Donn Harrison and Kathryn Harrison (Farrar)., Undated
    - STORE-010 - The Triangle Store at intersection of Georgetown Pike and Route 7 run by James Moore then by Harry Seville., Undated
    - THEL-002 - The River Bend Store owned by Frank Feighery for a few years., Undated
    - TRAM-001 - The Trammel Family., Undated
    - TURNER-003 - Mark Turner's House built 1892 on Route 193 near Springvale Road., 1979 April
    - WERN-004 - Buck's Store Economy Service., Undated
    - WERN-005 - Buck Werner's Economy Service Store. Jimmy Whetzel standing in doorway., Undated
    - WERN-006 - B.H. (Buck) Werner's Economy Service Store once run by O.K. Miller., Undated
    - WINSTON-001 - Elkins Station at Georgetown Pike and Old Dominion Drive on the Great Falls & Old Dominion Railroad line taken April 1916. Left to right are Eunice, Ruth, William, Thomas and Mrs. Franike Winston, April 1916., Undated
    - WODRR-002 - Washington & Old Dominion Railway Station, Great Falls, Va., c. 1917., Undated
    - WYNKOOP-011 - Photo collage: Wynkoops ran this farm on Walker Road near Great Falls, Va; Dr. Murphy's House; Dr. Murphy's House 1950s; Dr. Murphy's House as it looks today., Undated
    - Photo collage, Willard Wood, Vernon Bradford, Gertrude Bazzle, Norman F. Bradford Sr., and Howard Bradford, Undated
    - Photo collage, Ora Dickey Trammel and son Vincent, Della Dickey, Alice Dickey, Will Dickey, and Minnie Dickey, Undated
    - Laminated 1938 copy of Mark Turner's Virginia Milk Commission appointment, Undated
    - Laminated 1982 Great Falls Grange Washington Post article, Undated
  - Sub-series 8-6: Digital Photos, 2005-2015
    - Great Falls Fire Station Dedication [3 DVDs], 2012 March 10
    - Towlston Grange, Undated
    - GFHS Tour, 2015 May 21
    - Jackson House, 2012
    - Dairy Barns of Great Falls, 2012
    - GFHS Photo Scans [2 DVDs], 2005
    - 1993-2006 GFHS Calendars, Undated
- Series 9: Artwork, Undated-2010
  - Sign, "Old Georgetown Pike Toll Gate Admission 25 cts.", Undated
  - Sign, "Thelma's Country Store Homemade Ice Cream", Undated
  - Watercolor print, "Hickory Vale Shadows" by Susanne Riva, Undated
  - Watercolor print, "Merryhill" by Susanne Riva, Undated
  - Watercolor print, "White Pines Spring" by Susanne Riva, Undated
  - Watercolor print, "White Pines Remembered" by Susanne Riva, Undated
  - Framed charcoal sketch, "Red Barn" by Constance Nelson, 2010 August